<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>puzzle on dianyang.blog</title>
    <link>https://dianyang.blog/tags/puzzle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in puzzle on dianyang.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 22:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dianyang.blog/tags/puzzle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Helltaker</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/helltaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 22:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/helltaker/</guid>
      <description>Finally got around to playing Helltaker. It&amp;rsquo;s short and sweet and I had a great time with it.
After solving each puzzle level, you&amp;rsquo;re presented with a short dialogue and two dialogue choices. If you pick the wrong choice, you have to redo the entire level! The choices tend to be nonsensical, and picking the right choice is essentially a coin toss.
This seems like obviously terrible design, but I found that it forced me to actually read the text in trying to make an educated guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Tiny Islands</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/tiny-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 18:09:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/tiny-islands/</guid>
      <description>I played Tiny Islands a while back and very much preferred it over Islanders, mainly because the grid makes things much clearer. Both games are quite relaxing, and have great aesthetics.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy such games though, as the min-maxing involved usually feels too much like work. It was fascinating to hear the developer talk about designing the scoring system around what looked visually appealing to him. I guess scoring systems for these games tend to be fairly arbitrary anyway, so you might as well try to steer players toward something beautiful?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Rupert Reset</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/rupert-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 20:23:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/rupert-reset/</guid>
      <description>Rupert Reset is a puzzle platformer made for a game jam, where you can reset certain objects in each level to their original state. It&amp;rsquo;s very similar to Braid, in which only glowing items are immune to time manipulation. The art is very polished and cute; the &amp;ldquo;snow-bear&amp;rdquo; main character is quite unique!
There were a few interesting applications of the mechanics, though I felt like the spikes were mostly just unnecessary distractions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Cipher</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 17:04:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/cipher/</guid>
      <description>In Cipher you solve a series of abstract puzzles while figuring out the rules. It&amp;rsquo;s probably inspired by The Witness?
As you progress through the levels, the game introduces surprising concepts while maintaining a small ruleset. It achieves this by first showing narrower applications of rules, before revealing the more general cases. For example, dots are always placed outside of the 1x1 squares in earlier levels, but subsequently they can appear outside.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>