<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on dianyang.blog</title>
    <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on dianyang.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 09:41:47 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dianyang.blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaffolding</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/scaffolding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 09:41:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/scaffolding/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Our external, visible bodily life is similar to scaffolding supporting a building. The scaffolding itself is only necessary while the building is under construction. When the building is finished the scaffolding is no longer necessary and can be removed. It is the same with our bodily life. The body is only there to support the construction of our spiritual life, and as soon as that has been completed, the body can disappear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Mimic</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/mimic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 14:21:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/mimic/</guid>
      <description>Mimic is a single level prototype with quite a unique mechanic: mimic an animal&amp;rsquo;s movement pattern to take its form.
Animals are differentiated by the terrain they can move on, so you will get stuck unless you transform beside the correct adjacent terrains.
Terrains are also laid out to constrain player movement, which then feeds back into the animal forms you can take on. Another way to get stuck is to be confined such that you cannot mimic other animal movement patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating Elephants</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/eating-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 11:35:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/eating-elephants/</guid>
      <description>Q: How do you eat an elephant?
A: One bite at a time.
 Sometimes I forget things that are obviously true.
Like the fact that there are only so many days in a lifetime, and only so many minutes in a day.
Or that the people I admire worked insanely hard to achieve what they did, and so must I.
These are the invariants.
When the journey is long and uncomfortable,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Rupert Reset</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/rupert-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 20:23:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/rupert-reset/</guid>
      <description>Rupert Reset is a puzzle platformer made for a game jam, where you can reset certain objects in each level to their original state. It&amp;rsquo;s very similar to Braid, in which only glowing items are immune to time manipulation. The art is very polished and cute; the &amp;ldquo;snow-bear&amp;rdquo; main character is quite unique!
There were a few interesting applications of the mechanics, though I felt like the spikes were mostly just unnecessary distractions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] I Love Hue Too</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/i-love-hue-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 20:47:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/i-love-hue-too/</guid>
      <description>I Love Hue Too is a simple mobile puzzle game about rearranging colors according to their hues.
I played mostly by intuition and had a relaxing, pleasurable experience. (You&amp;rsquo;re shown the fewest possible number of moves though, and the world average, if you want more challenge.)
I wonder if the game trains you to better discern hues. Probably?
The levels are satisfying to complete in a way that&amp;rsquo;s subtly different from most other puzzle games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Cipher</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 17:04:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/cipher/</guid>
      <description>In Cipher you solve a series of abstract puzzles while figuring out the rules. It&amp;rsquo;s probably inspired by The Witness?
As you progress through the levels, the game introduces surprising concepts while maintaining a small ruleset. It achieves this by first showing narrower applications of rules, before revealing the more general cases. For example, dots are always placed outside of the 1x1 squares in earlier levels, but subsequently they can appear outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Disney Sorcerer&#39;s Arena</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/disney-sorcerers-arena/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 11:35:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/disney-sorcerers-arena/</guid>
      <description>I tried Disney Sorcerer&amp;rsquo;s Arena and really liked its streamlined combat, particularly the persistent target selection. When combat begins, an enemy target is selected by default. Players can switch target anytime, but otherwise the target remains the same each turn. This saves players an extra click most of the time when they perform an action, since the optimal strategy in most cases is to focus fire on one enemy anyway. (AOE actions hit all enemies instead of a subset of enemies, so targeting is skipped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>