<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on dianyang.blog</title>
    <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on dianyang.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 22:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dianyang.blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Helltaker</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/helltaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 22:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/helltaker/</guid>
      <description>Finally got around to playing Helltaker. It&amp;rsquo;s short and sweet and I had a great time with it.
After solving each puzzle level, you&amp;rsquo;re presented with a short dialogue and two dialogue choices. If you pick the wrong choice, you have to redo the entire level! The choices tend to be nonsensical, and picking the right choice is essentially a coin toss.
This seems like obviously terrible design, but I found that it forced me to actually read the text in trying to make an educated guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Tiny Islands</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/tiny-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 18:09:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/tiny-islands/</guid>
      <description>I played Tiny Islands a while back and very much preferred it over Islanders, mainly because the grid makes things much clearer. Both games are quite relaxing, and have great aesthetics.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy such games though, as the min-maxing involved usually feels too much like work. It was fascinating to hear the developer talk about designing the scoring system around what looked visually appealing to him. I guess scoring systems for these games tend to be fairly arbitrary anyway, so you might as well try to steer players toward something beautiful?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groundhog Week</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/groundhog-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 09:23:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/groundhog-week/</guid>
      <description>Groundhog Day&amp;lsquo;s premise seems curious, until you realize that most of us are living and reliving &amp;ldquo;Groundhog Weeks&amp;rdquo;.
But we are not &amp;ldquo;trapped&amp;rdquo; in a time loop.
Repetition isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily bad, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be boring. Consistency has a compounding effect, and there can be exciting growth within cycles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Lost Cities</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/lost-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 10:34:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/lost-cities/</guid>
      <description>I bought Lost Cities on iOS after hearing about it on The Spelunky Showlike podcast. It&amp;rsquo;s the digital adaptation of the original board game by Reiner Knizia.
It&amp;rsquo;s inspiring how much depth is packed into such simple rules. New strategies occur to me as I play, and it&amp;rsquo;s not always clear if I&amp;rsquo;m making the best move. I&amp;rsquo;m still working my way through the AI opponents, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to playing against other online players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaguely Titled</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/vaguely-titled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 17:43:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/vaguely-titled/</guid>
      <description>I came across a post titled Human Programming Interface recently.
Imagine being able to program your own behavior and emotions. We may be able to do literally that one day, but until then a will-powered, self-enforced prototype will have to suffice. What if you exhaustively defined a set of rules detailing how you should behave in every conceivable scenario, and then committed to it? That would be transformative.
That&amp;rsquo;s what I thought the post would be about, but it was about something else entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Soul Builder</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/soul-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 22:09:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/soul-builder/</guid>
      <description>Soul Builder is a short &amp;ldquo;idle&amp;rdquo; game with worker placement mechanics.
You have to sacrifice workers to construct certain buildings. There&amp;rsquo;s no real choice involved because the construction of these buildings constitute the winning condition. The optimal time to sacrifice workers is obvious, but efficiency doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter much since you will accumulate enough resources eventually.
Maybe the game is trying to encourage you to question the morality of sacrificing these workers, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was the intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaffolding</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/scaffolding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 09:41:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/scaffolding/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Our external, visible bodily life is similar to scaffolding supporting a building. The scaffolding itself is only necessary while the building is under construction. When the building is finished the scaffolding is no longer necessary and can be removed. It is the same with our bodily life. The body is only there to support the construction of our spiritual life, and as soon as that has been completed, the body can disappear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Mimic</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/mimic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 14:21:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/mimic/</guid>
      <description>Mimic is a single level prototype with quite a unique mechanic: mimic an animal&amp;rsquo;s movement pattern to take its form.
Animals are differentiated by the terrain they can move on, so you will get stuck unless you transform beside the correct adjacent terrains.
Terrains are also laid out to constrain player movement, which then feeds back into the animal forms you can take on. Another way to get stuck is to be confined such that you cannot mimic other animal movement patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating Elephants</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/eating-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 11:35:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/eating-elephants/</guid>
      <description>Q: How do you eat an elephant?
A: One bite at a time.
 Sometimes I forget things that are obviously true.
Like the fact that there are only so many days in a lifetime, and only so many minutes in a day.
Or that the people I admire worked insanely hard to achieve what they did, and so must I.
These are the invariants.
When the journey is long and uncomfortable,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Rupert Reset</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/rupert-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 20:23:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/rupert-reset/</guid>
      <description>Rupert Reset is a puzzle platformer made for a game jam, where you can reset certain objects in each level to their original state. It&amp;rsquo;s very similar to Braid, in which only glowing items are immune to time manipulation. The art is very polished and cute; the &amp;ldquo;snow-bear&amp;rdquo; main character is quite unique!
There were a few interesting applications of the mechanics, though I felt like the spikes were mostly just unnecessary distractions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] I Love Hue Too</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/i-love-hue-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 20:47:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/i-love-hue-too/</guid>
      <description>I Love Hue Too is a simple mobile puzzle game about rearranging colors according to their hues.
I played mostly by intuition and had a relaxing, pleasurable experience. (You&amp;rsquo;re shown the fewest possible number of moves though, and the world average, if you want more challenge.)
I wonder if the game trains you to better discern hues. Probably?
The levels are satisfying to complete in a way that&amp;rsquo;s subtly different from most other puzzle games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Cipher</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 17:04:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/cipher/</guid>
      <description>In Cipher you solve a series of abstract puzzles while figuring out the rules. It&amp;rsquo;s probably inspired by The Witness?
As you progress through the levels, the game introduces surprising concepts while maintaining a small ruleset. It achieves this by first showing narrower applications of rules, before revealing the more general cases. For example, dots are always placed outside of the 1x1 squares in earlier levels, but subsequently they can appear outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Game Notes] Disney Sorcerer&#39;s Arena</title>
      <link>https://dianyang.blog/posts/disney-sorcerers-arena/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 11:35:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dianyang.blog/posts/disney-sorcerers-arena/</guid>
      <description>I tried Disney Sorcerer&amp;rsquo;s Arena and really liked its streamlined combat, particularly the persistent target selection. When combat begins, an enemy target is selected by default. Players can switch target anytime, but otherwise the target remains the same each turn. This saves players an extra click most of the time when they perform an action, since the optimal strategy in most cases is to focus fire on one enemy anyway. (AOE actions hit all enemies instead of a subset of enemies, so targeting is skipped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>